Register of the Dieter Spethmann Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- THYSSEN GENERAL BUSINESS MEETING (HAUPTVERSAMMLUNG) FILE, 1970-1991
  - Minutes (Stenographische Aufzeichnungen)
    - 1985 Mar. 22 (Box 110)
    - 1986 Mar. 21 (Box 107)
    - 1987 Mar. 27 (Box 108)
    - 1988 Mar. 25 (Box 107)
    - 1989 Mar. 17 (Box 107)
    - 1990 Mar. 23 (Box 107)
    - 1991 Mar. 21 (Box 107)
- THYSSEN SUBJECT FILE, 1966-1996(bulk 1985-1991)
  - Affiliated group survey (Konzernübersicht), 1990 (Box 113)
  - Auditor's report, etc. (Prüfungsbericht, usw.) for the year ending
    - 1988 Sep. 30 (Box 123)
    - 1989 Sep. 30 (Box 123)
    - 1990 Sep. 30 (Box 121-123)
  - DA/TVV/TBV/AR materials (Materialsammlung), Winter 1986. (Box 111)
    Includes draft letter to Martin Bangemann
  - Departure [of Spethmann] (Abschied), 1990-1991 (Box 111)
  - Eurofabe report (Vortrag), Gangolf Weiler, 1984 May 17-18. (Box 111)
  - Fritz Thyssen Stiftung
    - General, 1983-1990. (Box 119)
      Includes correspondence, 1986-1990, and minutes, 1983-1990
    - Board of Trustees meeting records (Kuratoriumssitzung Unterlagen)
      - 1985 Jan. 26 - 1986 June 28. (Box 114)
        Includes letter from Gerhard Casper concerning honoraria practices, 1984 Oct. 17
      - 1987 Jan. 31 - 1989 July 1 (Box 115)
      - 1990 Jan. 20 - 1992 Feb. 8 (Box 115-116)
      - 1992 June 20 - 1994 Jan. 28-29 (Box 117)
      - 1994 July 2 - 1996 Jan. 27 (Box 114)
    - Funding cases miscellany (Unterstützungfälle Sonstiges), 1984-1989 (Box 116)
    - Projects (Projekte)
      - 1996/2, 1996
        - Miscellany and 1-25 (Box 120)
        - 26-69 (Box 121)
      - 1997/1, 1996
        - 1-40 (Box 118)
        - 41-67 (Box 119)
  - Partnership administration/asset management: By-laws, etc. (TBV/TVV {Thyssen Beteiligungsverwaltung/Thyssen Vermögensverwaltung}: Satzungen usw.), 1966-1987(bulk 1973-1987) (Box 125)
  - Planning, Thyssen AG; Thyssen-Welt/credit arrangement (Planung, Thyssen AG; Thyssen-Welt/Kreditdisposition), 1990-1991 (Box 113)
  - Presentations
    - Edinburgh supplementary materials (Präsentation Edinburgh Ergänzende Materialsammlung), 1989 Apr. 17 (Box 111)
    - Internationale Aktionärsmesse, Düsseldorf, 1990 Aug. 31 (Box 113)
  - Rheinstahl [merger], 1972-1976 (Box 124)
  - Statement of the economic development of the Thyssen Group according to business divisions and associations (Darstellung der wirtschaftlichen Entwicklung der Thyssen-Gruppe nach Geschaftsbereichen und Gesellschaften) for the years
    - 1973 to 1983 (Box 123)
    - 1973 to 1984 (Box 123)
  - Steel
    - Crisis, Reuter interview with Dr. Schulz (Stahlkrise Reuter-Interview mit Dr. Schulz), 1991 June 10 (Box 124)
    - Discussion (Stahlgespräch), Dr. Gangolf Weiler interview by Makoto Hiranuma, 1988 Feb. 9. (Box 113)
  - Supervisory board (Aufsichtsgremien Thyssen)
    - Corporation register, special sheets (AG Register, Sonderblätter), 1989-1991 (Box 112)
    - Subsidiaries (Töchter)
      - General, 1989-1991 (Box 112)
      - By-laws, etc. (AG Tochter-Satzungen usw.), 1980-1989 (Box 112)
  - TZT meetings (Sitzung), 1988-1990 (Box 126)
  - Thyssen and East Germany (Thyssen und die DDR), 1990 (Box 113)
- SUPERVISORY BOARD FUNCTIONS IN OTHER COMPANIES FILE, 1979-1995
  - General. Memories (Erinnerungen), 1979-1986 (Box 127)
  - Air Liquide Advisory Committee, 1988-1994. (Box 128)
    Primarily in English, some German and French
  - Dresdner Bank
    - Business report (Geschäftsbericht)
      - 1986 (Box 127)
      - 1988 (Box 130)
    - Numbers (Zahlen)
      - And graphics concerning business development (und Grafiken zur Geschäftsentwicklung)
        - 1986 November (Box 127)
        - 1989 April (Box 130)
      - Concerning economic development (zur Wirtschaftsentwicklung)
        - 1987 March (Box 127)
        - 1989 April (Box 130)
  - Merck
    - Board of Directors meeting, Rome, 1990 May 20-23. (Box 131)
    - European Advisory Council meetings, 1983-1991. (Box 131)
      Primarily in English
  - Münchener-Rückversicherungs-Gesellschaft, Komplex "Balsam AG," clippings, 1994-1995 (Box 130)
  - Unilever
    - Miscellany (Verschiedenes), 1974-1992(bulk 1991-1992). (Box 129)
    - Deutsche Unilever Gruppe
      - Advisory board meeting (Beiratssitzung) background material
        - 1989 June 26 (Box 130)
        - 1990 June 2 (Box 130)
      - Business report (Geschäftsbericht), 1984-1992 (Box 129)
    - Memorandum and articles of association, 1994 May. (Box 131)
    - Press releases, 1990-1991. (Box 131)
    - Supervisory Board - Quarterly reports, annual reports (Verwaltungsrat - Quartalsberichte, Jahresberichte), 1989-1992. (Box 129)
  - Voith. Miscellany (verschiedenes Informationen), 1992-1993 (Box 131)
  - Volvo International Advisory Board, 1991-1993. (Box 127)
- INDUSTRIAL CIRCLE GUESTBOOKS AND LIST (INDUSTRIEKREIS GÄSTEBÜCHER UND AUFSTELLUNG), 1955-2001
  - Guestbooks
    - 1955-1965 (Box 132)
    - 1955-1982 (Box 132)
    - 1966-1977 (Box 132)
    - 1982-1989 (Box 133)
    - 1990-2001 (Box 133)
  - List of guests, 1966-2001 (Box 132)
- INDUSTRIAL CIRCLE GATHERINGS (ZUSAMMENKÜNFTE) FILE, 1966-2001
  - 1966-1979 (Box 134)
  - 1980-1983 (Box 135)
  - 1984-1986 (Box 136)
  - 1987-1990 (Box 137)
  - 1991-1993 (Box 138)
  - 1994-1996 (Box 139)
  - 1997-1999 (Box 140)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 141)
- INDUSTRIAL CIRCLE CORRESPONDENCE (KORRESPONDENZ), 1971-2001(bulk 1980s-1990s)
  - General
    - General
      - 1976-1990 (Box 141)
      - 1990-1999 (Box 141)
      - 2000
    - Tax accountant office (Steuerberater Finanzamt), Bonn, 1971-1992 (Box 141)
  - Guests of honor (Ehrengäste)
    - Period prior to Klaus Blech, guests prior to 1994, correspondence 1975(?)-1999
      - A-B (Box 142)
      - Be-Bu (Box 145)
      - C-Franç (Box 146)
      - Frank-Fu (Box 143)
      - G-H (Box 147)
      - I-K (Box 148)
      - L (Box 149)
      - Ma-Mo (Box 150)
      - Mu-O (Box 151)
      - P-Q (Box 151)
      - R-S (Box 152)
      - Sch-T (Box 153)
      - Sta-Str (Box 154)
      - U-V (Box 154)
      - W-Z (Box 155)
    - Klaus Blech period, guests 1994 Jan. 1 - 2001 Jan. 31, correspondence 1971(?)-2001
      - A-G (Box 156)
      - H-K (Box 156)
      - L-Sp (Box 157)
      - Sch-Z (Box 157)
  - Members of businesses (Firmenmitglieder)
    - Companies
      - A-C (Box 143)
      - D-L (Box 143)
      - M-R (Box 144)
      - S-Z (Box 144)
    - Individuals, A-Z (Box 144)
- HANS SPETHMANN FILE, 1933-1954
  - Das Ruhrgebiet
    - Volumes 1-2, 1933. (Box 158)
      Printed copy
    - Volume 3, 1938. (Box 159)
  - "Der Ruhrbergbau und der Zweite Weltkrieg," short version (Kurzausgabe), 1954. (Box 159)
- AUDIOCASSETTE, 2002
  - Spethmann interview, Hoover Institution Archives, 2002 Mar. 14. (Box 159)
    Duration 1 hour
- VIDEOCASSETTE, 2002
  - Spethmann interview, "Continuity and Change in the German Steel Industry," with Gerald D. Feldman, 2002 Mar. 15., See also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE (Box 159)
    Number 234 in series "Conversations," Institute of International Studies, University of Calfornia, Berkeley (VHS, 44 minutes). In English.
- COMPACT DISC, 2002
  - Spethmann's numbered speeches and writings, 1-28, 28a, 29-80, 2002., See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/Numbered items (Box 159)
    The file "Vortrag0" is an item list of the CD contents. It appears that file "Vortrag28a" is actually the speech identified as "Vortrag28," and both "Vortrag27" and "Vortrag28" are versions of the file identified as "Vortrag27." The files were created in Microsoft Word in 2002, and are stored on a Fujifilm CD-R silver disc.
- Incremental Materials (Box 160-161)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.